Guide to the University Reports Reference Collection, 1959-ongoing UA.01.11.0045
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
University Reports Reference collection
1959-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0045
5.8 Linear Feet
The University Reports Reference Collection contains major reports concerning accreditation, university administration and governance, strategic planning, the curriculum, facilities, and student life. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The University Reports Reference Collection were acquired by the University Archives over time.
Collection Overview
The University Reports Reference Collection contains major reports concerning accreditation, university administration and governance, strategic planning, the curriculum, facilities, and student life. There are cataloged copies of many of these reports.
Related Material
DukeSpace at Duke University > University Archives > Campus publications and reports
Duke University Archives
- Accreditation Reports, 1965-ongoing
  - Bibliography (Box 1)
  - Self-Study Report, Duke University, 1965
    - Central Report (Box 1)
    - Aerospace Studies & Naval Science (Box 1)
    - Divinity School (Box 1)
    - Duke University Hospital (Box 1)
    - Graduate School of Arts & Sciences (Box 1)
    - Health & Physical Education (Box 1)
    - Humanities (Box 1)
    - Natural Sciences (Box 1)
    - School of Forestry (Box 1)
  - Self-Study Report, Duke University, 1965 (continued) (Box 2)
    - School of Law (Box 2)
    - Social Science Council (Box 2)
    - Social Sciences (Box 2)
    - Trinity College (Box 2)
    - The Woman's College (Box 2)
  - Continuing Self-Evaluation: Developing the Process, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Crossing Boundaries: Interdisciplinary Planning for the Nineties, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Balancing the Roles of the Research University, 1998 (Box 2)
- Strategic Planning, 1959-ongoing
  - Planning and Development at Duke University: First Progress Report / The University Committee on Long-Range Planning, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Long-Range Planning at Duke University: Second Progress Report / The University Committee on Long-Range Planning, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Duke University in the Decade Ahead: Third Progress Report / The University Committee on Long-Range Planning, 1961 (Box 3)
  - The Fifth Decade, Duke University, Fall 1964 (Box 3)
  - Duke's Fifth Decade: One University's Response to the Demands of Our Time, September 1965 (Box 3)
  - Profile of Duke University 1956-1976: Part 1 Statistical Material, 1966 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Profile of Duke University, 1956 to 1976, Part II: Descriptive Material, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Duke University Commission on University Governance, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Interim Report: The Board of Trustees (Box 3)
  - Interim Report: Central Administration (Box 3)
  - Interim Report: Departmental Governance (Box 3)
  - Report of the University Planning Committee, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Summary Report of the University Planning Committee, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Planning for the Eighties: A Report to the Duke University Board of Trustees / A. Kenneth Pye, 1978 (two copies, one disbound for copying) (Box 4)
  - Directions for Progress: A Report to the Duke University Board of Trustees / A. Kenneth Pye, 1980 (two copies, one disbound for copying) (Box 4)
  - Academic Plan, Duke University - Working Draft, Vol. I / Office of the Provost, 1987 [no Volume II, and no non-draft version] (Box 4)
  - Resource Utilization and Enrollment at Duke University / Office of the Provost, 1991 (Box 4)
  - A Duke Plan: Positioning for the Twenty-First Century, Draft / Office of the Provost, Office of the Executive Vice President for Administration, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Shaping Our Future: A Young University Faces a New Century / Duke University Strategic Planning Committee, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Duke University at the Millennium, 1999 / Provost John W. Strohbehn, January 1999 (Box 5)
  - Building on Excellence: the University Plan / Planning Steering Committee, 2001 (Box 5)
  - A Comparison of Duke University's Non-Faculty Benefit Programs with Those Offered by Other Universities and by Certain Local Industries and Non-Educational Institutions, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Together Duke: Advancing Excellence through Community, Academic Strategic Plan, September 2017 (Box 9)
- Schools and Divisions, 1964-ongoing
  - The Graduate School of Arts and Science, Duke University / Graduate Affairs Committee of the University Planning Committee,July 1964 (Box 6)
  - The Organization for Business and Finance, Duke University / Division of Business and Finance, January, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Preliminary Proposal for a Change from the College of Engineering to a School of Engineering / James L. Meriam, Dean, October, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Report of Self- Study / The Divinity School, Duke University, December 1983 (Box 6)
  - Office of the Registrar, Annual Statistical Report, 1969-1970, 1971-1972 (Box 6)
- Campus Planning, 1959-ongoing
  - Preliminary Development Report for West Campus Expansion / Olmsted Brothers, Landscape Architects, 1959 [related oversize materials in map cabinets] (Box 7)
  - A Center for the Fine Arts, Duke University / Raymond Lowey / William Snaith, Inc., 1962 (Box 7)
  - Campus Design Study, Duke University / Caudill, Rowlett and Scott, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Duke Planning Study, Phase 1 (Draft) / Caudill, Rowlett and Scott, 1963/64 (Box 7)
  - Duke University Campus Planning Study / Cudill, Rowlett and Scott, 1964 (Box 7)
    Related Materials
    See also: Parking and traffic reports, Duke University Police Department Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
  - Duke University Planning Study, Phase 2 / Caudill Rowlett and Scott, 1966 (Box 7)
  - A Proposal for the Scope, Site and Budget for a University Union / Subcommittee on the University Union of the Educational Facilities Committee, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Duke University Campus Planning Studies Progress Report / Dober and Associate, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Academic Priorities for Duke Forest / Land Resources Academic Uses Subcommittee, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Transportation Study, 1995 (Box 7)
- The Curriculum, 1968-ongoing
  - Varieties of Learning Experience ("The Krueger Report") / Subcommittee on Curriculum of the Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1968 (Box 8)
  - A Climate for Liberal Learning ("The Wardropper Report") / Special Committee on Educational Policy and Program in Trinity College, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Teacher Education at Duke University / Program in Education, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Report of the Task Force on Science and Engineering / The Task Force, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Curriculum 2000 / Curriculum Review Committee, 1999 (Box 8)
  - Structure and Choice in Liberal Education, Fall 1986 (Box 9)
- Student Life, 1955-ongoing
  - Report for the Committee for Study of Student Residential Life, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Final Report / Arts and Sciences Council Residential Life Committee, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Report / East Campus Enhancement Committee, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Building Community of Interest / Task Force on Intellectual Climate at Duke, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Final Report / Office of Student Affairs Task Force on Greek Life, 1994 (Box 9)
  - On Alcohol at Duke / Stephen Bryan, 2005 (Box 9)